<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>狗狗百科 on Dogecoin</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/</link><description>Recent content in 狗狗百科 on Dogecoin</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/zh-cn/dogepedia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do I backup a Dogecoin wallet?</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/articles/how-to-backup-a-wallet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zh-cn/dogepedia/articles/how-to-backup-a-wallet/</guid><description>A wallet is just a collection of private keys and public keys.
Each one of the wallet’s private keys is a randomised 256-bit number unique to your wallet, and it is what you need to be able to access and spend your coins. Your public address - the address which other Dogecoin wallets can use to send Dogecoin to your wallet - is a hashed version of the public key associated with the private key.</description></item><item><title>A whale holds nearly 30% of Dogecoin supply! Is this true?</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zh-cn/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</guid><description>A common source of FUD surrounding Dogecoin is the claim that certain wallets holding a large percentage of the supply are owned by private investors or so-called &amp;ldquo;whales&amp;rdquo;. In reality, many of the top Dogecoin wallets are cold wallets or hot wallets controlled by exchanges and brokers, and they thus represent Dogecoin held in custody for thousands - or hundreds of thousands, even - of people.
To those accustomed to blockchain analysis, many of those wallets appear as wallets managed by trading platforms, as they exhibit patterns of activity and volume that were typical of crypto exchanges or brokerage services holding large amounts of collateral.</description></item><item><title>如何成为一个狗狗币开发者？</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zh-cn/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</guid><description>狗狗币是一个开源项目，这意味着在技术上知行合一的任何人都可以为狗狗币的开发做出贡献。就算你是新手，学习新技巧也都永远不晚！
狗狗币有一个了不起的开发者和志愿者团队，他们致力于欢迎新人加入，并帮助他们学习和发展他们的技能。这个社区也特别鼓舞人心，时常可以看到老狗们在帮助新来的狗子们。
狗狗币有很多你可以帮助的项目：Core、Libdogecoin、Gigawallet、文档和网站等等。正如狗狗币基金会的Timothy Stebbing所强调的：只要拿起你的铲子，你就可以成为狗狗币的开发者！开源社区崇尚任人唯贤：你做得越多，你就越受尊重，你就越能成为自己所期待的样子！
狗狗币的开发者们对这些能搞起狗狗币生态的人所带来的进步充满热情。为此，Libdogecoin背后的一个关键目标是为许多编程语言建立捆绑，这样狗狗币就可以更广泛地面向开发人员。
如果你想为狗狗币的技术开发做出贡献，成为狗狗币的开发者，请看看GitHub上Dogecoin Core和狗狗币基金会的项目，并参与进来！</description></item><item><title>狗狗币毫无用处!</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zh-cn/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</guid><description>不，狗狗币有用，而且它一直很有用！一个简单的事实是，钱是有用的，而狗狗币就是钱! 而且，狗狗币是少见的为成为货币这一目标而生的加密货币。
狗狗币起初因玩笑而生，他过去很好的遵循了这个传统，未来也将保持这个传统。狗狗币自诞生之日起，就被作为小费用于激励人们做一些有意义的事情：赞助牙买加雪橇队参加冬奥会、建造肯尼亚水井、建造狗狗币汽车以及许多狗狗币社区支持的疯狂创意。作为一种打赏货币，狗狗币始终保持了它诞生之初的用途，相较于同期的其他货币，狗狗币区块链上的交易费率低廉，交易速度更快。
经过多年发展，使用狗狗币在网上商店进行消费已经成为可能。过去两年，随着狗狗币支付集成到第三方支付比如BitPay、Coinbase及一些支持狗狗币的预付卡提供商，狗狗币的使用呈爆发态势。商店还可以通过JSON-RPC接口直接集成到狗狗币区块链上。狗狗币基金会正在同开发者一起，计划通过创建一些标准化、流程化的软件包，来使得狗狗币支付更便捷。
我们正在进行开发，以增强狗狗币相较其他加密货币在实用性上的优势。随着好几个团队持续建设狗狗币及其生态，狗狗币还将找到新的实用场景。
根据狗狗币宣言，狗狗币秉承实用原则、友好原则、开放原则以及稳健原则，同时要保持独特的快乐文化。</description></item><item><title>What is a mining pool?</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zh-cn/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/</guid><description>Mining pools are services, operated by third parties not affiliated with Dogecoin, which allow a group of miners to combine their hashing power when attempting to solve the &amp;ldquo;puzzles&amp;rdquo; involved in mining Dogecoin.
Mining rewards - consisting of 10,000 Dogecoin per block plus transaction fees associated to the transactions included in the block - are awarded to the miner who discovers a valid Proof of Work for a new block before any other miner in the network.</description></item><item><title>狗狗币如何运转?</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/articles/how-does-dogecoin-work/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zh-cn/dogepedia/articles/how-does-dogecoin-work/</guid><description>魔法和模因文化！（开玩笑的啦~）
重中之重: 狗狗币是货币。
和其他流行的加密货币一样, 狗狗币通过区块链技术运转。但是，和其他绝大多数加密货币不同，狗狗币的交易费用非常低，交易确认的速度又非常快。
首先，如果你想向世界上任何地方的某个人寄一笔钱或者收一笔钱，但是你又不想使用中心化的银行从而需要支付外币兑换和转账费用，那么狗狗币就是你的好选择！
除此之外，狗狗币还可以用来购买商品和服务，可以在Reddit和Twitter这样的社交平台上打赏小费，更多关于狗狗币用途和运转方式的信息，请参阅社区和生态!
深度了解! 如果你想了解更多狗狗币是如何运转的，请点击查看以下更深入的资料。
什么是区块链 什么是节点 什么是矿工 什么是矿池</description></item><item><title>Operate a Dogecoin Node</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zh-cn/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/</guid><description>The Dogecoin network is a peer-to-peer payment network consisting of thousands of computers called nodes. Each of these nodes is running specialized software. Dogecoin Core, Dogecoin&amp;rsquo;s reference implementation, is the software more commonly used to run a Dogecoin node. It can be downloaded from the official Dogecoin.com website and directly from the Github repository.
Running a full node is a service that volunteers in the network, called node operators, provide to the Dogecoin community.</description></item><item><title>Can you put a cap on Dogecoin?</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zh-cn/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</guid><description>Right now, and for the next hundred years or so, Dogecoin operates like, and will continue to operate like, most other crypto assets. “Capped” assets are nowhere near mined out – and will continue adding to their supply, just like Dogecoin, for the foreseeable future.
Dogecoin’s supply is not unlimited, because it has an absolute limit of issuance per block, per day, per year – just like other coins do. The only difference is that Dogecoin’s issuance does not have an end date.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin Inflation</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-inflation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zh-cn/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-inflation/</guid><description>Dogecoin has a diminished inflation rate because it has a fixed yearly issuance of 5 billion coins. This means that each year, the rate of inflation decreases comparative to the total supply, and in a very predictable way, making Dogecoin the perfect candidate to be used as a currency.
Since Dogecoin is not meant to be hoarded — and hoarding is a major barrier to a cryptocurrency being used as, well, an actual currency — Dogecoin will have a much more utilitarian and practical place in the economy than other cryptocurrencies, which often remain unspent.</description></item><item><title>How can I help?</title><link>/zh-cn/dogepedia/articles/how-can-i-help-doge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/zh-cn/dogepedia/articles/how-can-i-help-doge/</guid><description>There are so many ways to get involved and support Dogecoin. From making memes and artworks – to educating people who are new to crypto: there are endless possibilities for you to get involved and to help the Dogecoin movement.
A good place to start is by joining one or more of the highly active communities on platforms such as Reddit, Twitter, and Discord.
If you have a technical background and would like to contribute to Dogecoin technical development, you can get involved via Dogecoin Core and The Dogecoin Foundation GitHub repositories.</description></item></channel></rss>