<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dogecoin</title><link>/es/</link><description>Recent content on Dogecoin</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>es</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/es/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do I backup a Dogecoin wallet?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/how-to-backup-a-wallet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/how-to-backup-a-wallet/</guid><description>&lt;p>A wallet is just a collection of &lt;em>private keys&lt;/em> and &lt;em>public keys&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each one of the wallet’s private keys is a randomised 256-bit number unique to your wallet, and it is what you need to be able to access and spend your coins. Your public address - the address which other Dogecoin wallets can use to send Dogecoin to your wallet - is a hashed version of the public key associated with the private key.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A whale holds nearly 30% of Dogecoin supply! Is this true?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</guid><description>&lt;p>A common source of FUD surrounding Dogecoin is the claim that certain wallets holding a large percentage of the supply are owned by private investors or so-called &amp;ldquo;whales&amp;rdquo;. In reality, many of the top Dogecoin wallets are cold wallets or hot wallets controlled by exchanges and brokers, and they thus represent Dogecoin held in custody for thousands - or hundreds of thousands, even - of people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To those accustomed to blockchain analysis, many of those wallets appear as wallets managed by trading platforms, as they exhibit patterns of activity and volume that were typical of crypto exchanges or brokerage services holding large amounts of collateral. In particular, the Dogecoin community has identified the exchanges and brokerage platforms behind some of the largest wallets, including the infamous &amp;ldquo;whale&amp;rdquo; holding 30% of the supply. This was possible through a bit of community sleuthing that involved collecting circumstantial evidence and tracking deposits and withdrawals from exchanges to private wallets. As it turned out, that infamous whale wallet, which was split across &lt;a href="https://bitinfocharts.com/dogecoin/wallet/3334959">several addresses&lt;/a> in October/November 2021, contains the holdings of hundreds of thousands of retail holders.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogecoin has no utility!</title><link>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh yes it does, and it always has! The simple fact is that &lt;em>money has utility&lt;/em> - and Dogecoin &lt;em>is&lt;/em> money! Indeed, Dogecoin is one of the few crypto&lt;strong>currencies&lt;/strong> that has been used for this main purpose from day one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogecoin was first meant to be a joke - and it served, and will serve, this purpose very well. It almost immediately became a means to tip and encourage others to go and achieve something: the Jamaican bobsled team, the water wells in Kenya, the Dogecoin car, and many more crazy initiatives the community supported over the years. As a tipping currency, thanks to its low fees and speed of transactions in comparison to competing chains for a long part of its existence, Dogecoin has never stopped working for its intended use.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can I become a Dogecoin developer?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin is an open-source project, meaning that anyone with some technical know-how can contribute to Dogecoin’s technical development. Even if you’re new to the space, it’s never too late to learn new tricks!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogecoin has an amazing team of developers and volunteers who are committed to welcoming new people into the space and helping them to learn and develop their skills. The community is extremely encouraging, too, and it’s very common to see old Shibes helping new Shibes as they enter the space.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Does Dogecoin Work?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/how-does-dogecoin-work/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/how-does-dogecoin-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>Magic and memes! (Just kidding. Kind of.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First things first: Dogecoin &lt;em>is&lt;/em> money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like other popular cryptocurrencies, Dogecoin works by utilising &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-blockchain/">blockchain technology&lt;/a>. Unlike a lot of other popular cryptocurrencies, though, the fees to send Dogecoin are extremely small, and the speed by which Dogecoin transactions are confirmed is relatively fast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/11.png" alt="image info">
Simply put, if you would like to send money to someone who is located anywhere in the world — or receive money from someone who is located anywhere in the world — &lt;em>without&lt;/em> using a centralised bank and paying foreign currency exchange and transfer fees, then Dogecoin can work for you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a mining pool?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mining pools are services, operated by third parties not affiliated with Dogecoin, which allow a group of &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/">&lt;strong>miners&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> to combine their &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/#hashing-power">&lt;strong>hashing power&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> when attempting to solve the &amp;ldquo;puzzles&amp;rdquo; involved in mining Dogecoin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mining rewards&lt;/strong> - consisting of 10,000 Dogecoin per block plus transaction fees associated to the transactions included in the block - are awarded to the miner who discovers a valid Proof of Work for a new block before any other miner in the network. Anyhow, alone, a miner has a very limited hashing power in relation to the overall &lt;strong>Mining Hashrate&lt;/strong> of the network. This means a miner, even when using a powerful &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/how-tos/mining-dogecoin/#ASICs">&lt;strong>ASIC miner&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, has a small chance at being awarded the next block. In practice, it could take a long time before a solo miner finds a block and is awarded the rewards associated with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Operate a Dogecoin Node</title><link>/es/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Dogecoin network is a peer-to-peer payment network consisting of thousands of computers called &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/">&lt;strong>nodes&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>. Each of these nodes is running specialized software. &lt;strong>Dogecoin Core&lt;/strong>, Dogecoin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>reference implementation&lt;/em>, is the software more commonly used to run a Dogecoin node. It can be downloaded from the official &lt;a href="https://dogecoin.com/">&lt;strong>Dogecoin.com&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> website and directly from the &lt;a href="https://github.com/dogecoin/dogecoin/releases">&lt;strong>Github repository&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Running a &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/#full-nodes">&lt;strong>full node&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> is a service that volunteers in the network, called &lt;em>node operators&lt;/em>, provide to the Dogecoin community. Unlike what happens when mining, operating a node does not lead to direct incentives or rewards, but it makes the Dogecoin network more resilient, thus contributing to utility and adoption.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Can you put a cap on Dogecoin?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/7.png" alt="image info">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right now, and for the next hundred years or so, Dogecoin operates like, and will continue to operate like, most other crypto assets. “Capped” assets are nowhere near mined out – and will continue adding to their supply, just like Dogecoin, for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogecoin’s supply is &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> unlimited, because it has an absolute limit of issuance per block, per day, per year – just like other coins do. The only difference is that Dogecoin’s issuance does not have an end date. Therefore, Dogecoin is only “infinite” over “infinite time”. Over finite time, its issuance is, in fact, finite.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Charities Accepting Doge</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/charities-accepting-doge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/charities-accepting-doge/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin’s history includes many charitable endeavours: from funding clean water wells in 2014 for Kenya, to the #TeamSeas initiative in 2021 – and many worthwhile causes in-between. The past year, though, has seen a dramatic increase in charities directly accepting Dogecoin donations – which is very much wow!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Organisations like &lt;em>The Giving Block&lt;/em> make it super easy for charities to accept Dogecoin and other cryptocurrency donations. Initiatives like &lt;em>The Water Project&lt;/em> — which has been accepting Dogecoin for over 6-years — now use &lt;em>The Giving Block&lt;/em> to accept Dogecoin donations to fund fully monitored water projects in Africa. The &lt;em>American Cancer Society&lt;/em> is also another charity that utilises this service, and uses Dogecoin donations to help patients access lifesaving care and resources, as they work toward the goal of ridding the world from cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogecoin and coin burning</title><link>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-and-coin-burning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-and-coin-burning/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin does not need coin burning marketing mechanisms that new tokens and other chains have attempted to implement to artificially inflate their prices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simplez.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/8.png" alt="image info">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogecoin and Privacy</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-and-privacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-and-privacy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Privacy is an interesting topic, and one in which Dogecoin community members are actively involved. For starters, it’s worthwhile acknowledging that every transaction on the blockchain is public. That is, it’s possible for anyone to see any Dogecoin transaction that has ever been made if you have the public wallet address! This is why, if you wish to remain anonymous, it’s important not to claim any public address as yours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogecoin has no developers!</title><link>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-developers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, yes it does - and it always has!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogecoin’s primary purpose has always been to be used as a currency. Billy Markus, co-creator of Dogecoin with Jackson Palmer, acted as a solo developer for the first Dogecoin Core releases. In 2014, Billy and Jackson left Dogecoin development, and a new development team was formed. Over the years, the Dogecoin development team has consisted of a small group of maintainers coordinating the work of more than 40 contributors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogecoin Inflation</title><link>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-inflation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-inflation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin has a diminished inflation rate because it has a fixed yearly issuance of 5 billion coins. This means that each year, the rate of inflation &lt;strong>decreases&lt;/strong> comparative to the total supply, and in a very predictable way, making Dogecoin the perfect candidate to be used as a currency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since Dogecoin is not meant to be hoarded — and hoarding is a major barrier to a crypto&lt;strong>currency&lt;/strong> being used as, well, an actual &lt;strong>currency&lt;/strong> — Dogecoin will have a much more utilitarian and practical place in the economy than other cryptocurrencies, which often remain unspent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogecoin is a joke!</title><link>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-is-a-joke/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-is-a-joke/</guid><description>&lt;p>It is true that Dogecoin was born as a joke - and this sense of fun should forever remain and never go away! Despite Dogecoin’s genesis as a joke, though, more and more people are beginning to realise Dogecoin’s utilitarian value as a legitimate, efficient, and functional currency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of this, Dogecoin has now evolved into much &lt;em>more&lt;/em> than ‘&lt;em>just&lt;/em> a joke’, whilst still maintaining its LOL attitude. Indeed, as the late and great Sporklin once commented: “Dogecoin can be a joke and still be functional … While the branding is frontal jokes and memes, everything under that has been solid from the start”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can I get Dogecoin?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/get-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/get-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many ways to get your hands on Dogecoin: from exchanges, receiving tips, accepting Dogecoin for goods and services, and even from projects like Dogecoin Folding @ Home!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="exchanges">Exchanges&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A popular way people get their hands on Dogecoin is via an exchange. There are many exchanges on the market, and they are most commonly used to exchange fiat money for cryptocurrency, or to exchange cryptocurrency for fiat money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can purchase Dogecoin on an exchange at the current market price (this is called a market &lt;em>taker&lt;/em> transaction), or by making an offer to purchase cryptocurrency once it reaches a specified price (a market &lt;em>maker&lt;/em> transaction). Some exchanges only allow its users to purchase cryptocurrencies via market taker transactions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can I help?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/how-can-i-help-doge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/how-can-i-help-doge/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are &lt;em>so&lt;/em> many ways to get involved and support Dogecoin. From making memes and artworks – to educating people who are new to crypto: there are endless possibilities for you to get involved and to help the Dogecoin movement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good place to start is by joining one or more of the highly active communities on platforms such as &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dogecoin/">Reddit&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dogecoin">Twitter&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/dogecoin">Discord&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a technical background and would like to contribute to Dogecoin technical development, you can get involved via &lt;a href="https://github.com/dogecoin/dogecoin">Dogecoin Core&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/dogecoinfoundation">The Dogecoin Foundation&lt;/a> GitHub repositories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can I join the Dogecoin community?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/join-the-dogecoin-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/join-the-dogecoin-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many ways you can get involved in the Dogecoin community! Most popular social-media platforms have a thriving and welcoming Dogecoin community through which newcomers and old-timers alike can connect, discuss, and share their thoughts, memes, ideas, and spread the joy of all things Doge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Reddit&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Twitter&lt;/strong> are the most popular platforms for the Dogecoin community, with millions of active Shibes on either platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Reddit, &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/dogecoin/">r/dogecoin&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> is so popular that in 2021 it was ranked as Reddit’s Top community for cryptocurrency and finance, and posts in the Dogecoin subreddit are frequently the most upvoted posts for the entire Reddit platform! If you are more technically inclined and want to stay updated about Dogecoin development, you can also check out the technical development subreddit at &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/dogecoindev/">r/dogecoindev&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>. &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/dogeducation/">r/dogeducation&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> is another subreddit where new Dogecoin users can find How-Tos and help.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can I use Dogecoin to buy stuff from my favorite stores?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/using-dogecoin-in-a-store/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/using-dogecoin-in-a-store/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin is becoming increasingly popular as a payment option by merchants worldwide. Moreover, the implementation of third-party cryptocurrency payment solutions such as Coinbase Commerce and BitPay has resulted in more-and-more businesses accepting Dogecoin. It is also possible for you to indirectly use Dogecoin at merchants who don’t accept Dogecoin. For example, some companies have established relationships with credit card companies in which you can &amp;rsquo;top up&amp;rsquo; a credit card from your Dogecoin crypto wallet. Other companies even facilitate the payments of utilities and bills with Dogecoin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can my business accept Dogecoin?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/how-can-my-business-accept-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/how-can-my-business-accept-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>The past year has seen a wave of businesses starting to accept Dogecoin for goods and services. Thanks to a multitude of crypto payment solutions, now it’s as easy as ever for your business to accept Dogecoin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the most foundational level, for your business to accept Dogecoin in exchange for goods and services you will require a &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/">wallet&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a bricks-and-mortar business where payments are made in person, it’s common for merchants to print a QR code that is scanned by customers’ smartphones to streamline the transaction process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How do I get a Dogecoin wallet?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/</guid><description>&lt;p>A wallet is necessary for people wanting to trade, use, or ‘hodl’ Dogecoin. There are many ways you can get a wallet, and the best choice of wallet for you is dependent upon the purpose for which you intend to use your Dogecoin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Generally speaking, there are two overarching categories of wallets: &amp;lsquo;custodial&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;non-custodial&amp;rsquo;, depending on whether you are the sole holder of your wallet&amp;rsquo;s private key. Additionally, wallets can be &amp;lsquo;hot&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;cold&amp;rsquo;, depending on whether they are connected to the internet or not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How do I send and receive Dogecoin?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/send-and-receive-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/send-and-receive-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sending and receiving Dogecoin is very easy to do. Whether you intend to send or receive Dogecoin, in both cases you will need a &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/">wallet&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When sending Dogecoin from your wallet you will need to input a destination wallet address. This is a unique alphanumeric identifier that looks a bit like gibberish! Rest assured, though, a wallet address is certainly &lt;em>not&lt;/em> gibberish – but specifies a unique destination on the Dogecoin blockchain to which Dogecoin can be sent and stored.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is there a roadmap?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-roadmap/</guid><description>&lt;p>While a &amp;lsquo;roadmap&amp;rsquo; is a term that&amp;rsquo;s commonly used when new cryptocurrencies are released,
it also conveys a rigid way forward, led by a single ‘company’ or ‘lead developer’.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogecoin is a community-driven, consensus based open-source project and its direction is
formed by the many individual and organisational contributors to the various projects of
the Dogecoin blockchain &amp;amp; ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The direction of Dogecoin is paved by the &lt;a href="/dogepedia/projects/">many projects&lt;/a> that the
community feels best shape its direction. This is very intentional: it is important
that Dogecoin remains a decentralised project with shepherds rather than rulers, whose projects
and contributions stand or fall on their merits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is xxx project affiliated with The Dogecoin Foundation?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/is-this-project-affiliated-with-dogecoin-foundation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/is-this-project-affiliated-with-dogecoin-foundation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Making Memes</title><link>/es/dogepedia/how-tos/making-memes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/how-tos/making-memes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Memes are awesome, and they’re easy to make! There’s lots of meme maker websites, and even meme applications that you can install on your smartphone to makes memes on the run. You may even go one step further and create Dogecoin-themed meme templates which have a possibility of being seen by millions of others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What makes a great meme? Well, it needs to be funny and convey meaning in a concise and relatable form. Moreover, capturing the sentiment of a community – or peoples’ innermost thoughts and feelings that are not shared publicly – can form a great basis from which to create highly engaging and novel memes. The power of memes also comes from their accessibility and ability to be viewed by millions in a relatively short of amount of time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mining Dogecoin</title><link>/es/dogepedia/how-tos/mining-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/how-tos/mining-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Miners and mining are at the center of Dogecoin&amp;rsquo;s Proof of Work consensus mechanism. Check these Dogepedia articles to understand what miners do, how they interact with nodes, and why mining pools come into play when it comes to mining:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/">&lt;strong>What is a miner?&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/">&lt;strong>What is a mining pool?&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/">&lt;strong>What is a node?&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="mining-dogecoin">Mining Dogecoin&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Mining Dogecoin used to be much simpler in the early days. A miner only needed a computer with enough disk space and a gaming GPU - and this was enough to mine Dogecoin. Soon enough, the total &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/#hashing-power">&lt;strong>mining hashrate of the network&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> had grown so much that the likelihood of a miner finding a block while mining solo had been reduced drastically.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>/es/resources/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/resources/</guid><description>&lt;p>A list of resources created by shibes that can be useful to work with Dogecoin and to research it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tools-to-monitor-and-study-dogecoin-and-its-network">Tools to Monitor and Study Dogecoin and its Network&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://sochain.com/DOGE">SoChain - Dogecoin chain explorer.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://dogechain.info/">Dogechain - Dogecoin chain explorer.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://live.blockcypher.com/doge/">Blockcypher - Dogecoin chain explorer.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blockshibe.net">Blockshibe - monitor the work of miners and mining pools.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blockchair.com/dogecoin/nodes">Blockchair - monitor the number and versions of Dogecoin nodes in the network.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="shop-directories">Shop Directories&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cryptwerk.com/pay-with/doge/">Cryptwerk - a directory of shops accepting Dogecoin.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="third-party-providers-of-payment-integrations">Third Party Providers of Payment Integrations&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://commerce.coinbase.com/integrate">Coinbase - integration for Wordpress and Shopify.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://bitpay.com/integrations/">Bitpay - integrations for multiple platforms.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="communities">Communities&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/dogecoin">The Official Dogecoin community on reddit.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/dogecoindev">The Official Dogecoin development community on reddit.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/dogeducation">The Official Dogecoin community to help educating new and old shibes.&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The History of Dogecoin</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/history-of-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/history-of-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin was originally created as a joke in late 2013 by Billy Markus and Jackson Palmer. Both Billy and Jackson thought that cryptocurrency was being taken far too seriously and wasn’t much fun. Jackson created the Dogecoin.com website and would have been, for a while, the public face of Dogecoin, while Billy worked as a solo developer on the first 4 releases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/12.png" alt="image info">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On December 6th, 2013, Dogecoin was launched taking influence from the famous Doge meme: an image of a very adorable Shiba Inu dog with multi-coloured comic sans text that appears as the dog’s “thought bubbles”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What are the benefits of a hardware wallet, and how to use it with Doge?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>&lt;p>A hardware wallet is a device designed to store a user&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>private keys&lt;/em> securely, without ever exposing them to other external devices or the internet. For this reason, most hardware wallets are &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/">cold wallets&lt;/a> and are amongst the most secure methods for storing and using Dogecoin and other cryptos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually, hardware wallets can be connected to a PC or another device via a USB or Bluetooth connection. Through this connection, they can be used to sign a transaction occurring in a wallet application running on the external device (such as your PC). The transaction is signed inside the hardware wallet, and, unless the hardware wallet has been previously compromised, the private keys are never exposed to the outside world throughout this process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a blockchain?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-blockchain/</guid><description>&lt;p>A blockchain is a digital distributed ledger that is used as a system for validating and recording transaction information. This digital ledger of transactions is duplicated and distributed throughout an entire network of computers connected to the blockchain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Dogecoin blockchain consists of thousands of computers – called &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/">&lt;strong>nodes&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> – meaning that transaction information is not stored in one centralised place. Instead, Dogecoin blockchain information is stored across thousands of nodes. This is why cryptocurrencies like Dogecoin are often referred to as being &lt;em>decentralised&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a miner?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/</guid><description>&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Miner&lt;/strong> is a specialized &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/">node&lt;/a> in the Dogecoin network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After regular &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/#full-nodes">nodes&lt;/a> in the network, by referencing the blockchain, have verified that a Dogecoin transaction is valid, the transaction is shown in a &amp;ldquo;pending&amp;rdquo; state. It stays in this state until a &lt;strong>miner&lt;/strong> or a collective of miners known as a &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/">&lt;strong>mining pool&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> picks up the transaction.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="miners-eli5">Miners: ELI5&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Miners are nodes using special hardware (normally Scrypt ASIC miners) which allows them to solve cryptographic puzzles, in a process referred to as &amp;ldquo;mining&amp;rdquo;. A miner receives new transactions from the other nodes in the network, combines them in a &lt;strong>block&lt;/strong> following predetermined and inviolable rules enforced by the network, and then attempts to solve a puzzle that will generate a special number, called a hash, that is derived by combining the content of the block and a number called &lt;strong>nonce&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>number used once&lt;/em>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a node and why is it important? Do I need to run one?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Dogecoin network is a peer-to-peer payment network consisting of thousands of computers called nodes. Each of these nodes is running specialized software, called Dogecoin Core. Transaction information is recorded into a database, split into blocks chained to each other, and distributed and replicated across the nodes of the network: this database is known as the &lt;em>Dogecoin blockchain&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In practice, this results in transaction information being shared across the entire network and, subsequently, not needing to be stored in one centralized place. This is why cryptocurrencies like Dogecoin are often referred to as being &lt;em>decentralized&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a wallet, really?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-wallet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-wallet/</guid><description>&lt;p>A wallet is a set of private keys that gives you access to the control of certain coins on the blockchain ledger. When you spend a coin, control of that coin is transferred from being controlled by your keys to being controlled by someone else&amp;rsquo;s keys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A &lt;em>wallet app&lt;/em> (often referred to simply as a &amp;ldquo;wallet&amp;rdquo;) is an application which manages these keys, reports these amounts, and facilitates the transfer of amounts of coins between addresses. Some wallet apps store your keys locally; others store the keys on a remote server (which is less safe). Just remember: &lt;em>whoever has the keys controls the coins&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is Dogecoin Folding @ Home?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-folding-at-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-folding-at-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin Folding at Home is a charitable community-based distributed-computing project that utilises participants’ idle computer power to help scientists who are studying COVID-19, Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s, Huntington&amp;rsquo;s, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s, cancers and other diseases as they work towards finding cures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It uses a very simple GUI interface, and runs in the background using idle computer time via GPUs, CPUs, and ARM processors. Your computer will receive “work units”, and then sends the completed work units back to the FAH servers. These are then compiled with other work units into an overall statistical simulation pertaining to one or more diseases and their potential therapies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is Dogecoin?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/3.png" alt="image info">
Dogecoin is many things to many different people. At its heart, Dogecoin is the accidental crypto &lt;strong>movement&lt;/strong> that makes people smile!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is also an open-source peer-to-peer cryptocurrency that utilises &lt;a href="https://www.dogecoin.com/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-blockchain">blockchain technology&lt;/a>, a highly secure decentralised system of storing information as a public ledger that is maintained by a network of computers called &lt;a href="https://www.dogecoin.com/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node">nodes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More than this, though, is the ethos of Dogecoin, summarised in the &lt;a href="https://foundation.dogecoin.com/manifesto/">Dogecoin Manifesto&lt;/a>, and its amazing, vibrant community made up of friendly folks just like you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is the Dogecoin Foundation?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-the-dogecoin-foundation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/what-is-the-dogecoin-foundation/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Dogecoin Foundation is a not-for-profit organisation tasked with providing (i) support for Dogecoin through development and advocacy, (ii) Dogecoin trademark defence to prevent abuse and fraud, and (iii) a roadmap and governance for the future of Dogecoin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Foundation was initially established by members of the Dogecoin team in 2014 to provide governance and support for the Dogecoin project. In 2021 the Foundation was re-invigorated by members of the core development team — along with fresh faces and new seasoned advisors — ready to grow Dogecoin for the decade ahead!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What merchants currently accept Dogecoin?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/merchants-accepting-doge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/merchants-accepting-doge/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the time of writing, there is a rapidly expanding list of merchants who accept Dogecoin as a form of payment. Because of this, finding — and maintaining — an up-to-date directory of businesses that #AcceptDoge is no small feat!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to the overwhelming support from the Dogecoin community in encouraging — and then promoting — businesses that accept Dogecoin, we anticipate that the list of businesses that accept Dogecoin is only going to grow much larger and cover a variety of industries and sectors in the years to come. This is certainly the aim: the Dogecoin community is committed to seeing Dogecoin used as a viable alternative to traditional centralised fiat money.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who are the current Dogecoin developers?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-developers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>The development of Dogecoin is open, permissionless, and participatory. Over the years, a varied group of developers has contributed to the development of Dogecoin Core, Dogecoin&amp;rsquo;s reference implementation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogecoin was created by Billy Markus and Jackson Palmer in 2013. Billy worked on Dogecoin Core as its main developer for its first releases. Dogecoin Core started as a fork of Lucky Coin and Litecoin, themselves forks of Bitcoin Core. Dogecoin Core thus derived most of its codebase from the work Bitcoin developers had done on the Bitcoin repository.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who owns and controls the Dogecoin Network?</title><link>/es/dogepedia/articles/who-owns-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogepedia/articles/who-owns-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the wonderful things about Dogecoin is that no-one, or no corporate entity, “owns” the Dogecoin blockchain: it is entirely open-source, permissionless, decentralised, and peer-to-peer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Dogecoin network is “controlled” by the network of nodes through which it operates. Anyone can run a node, and to learn how to do so, &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/">click here&lt;/a>. Some nodes also &lt;a href="/es/dogepedia/how-tos/mining-dogecoin/">mine Dogecoin&lt;/a>, meaning they perform computational work as part of the process to both confirm all transactions up to the next block, and the next block. They are rewarded for this work with a block reward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>/es/legal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/legal/</guid><description>&lt;p>This Privacy Policy describes our policies and procedures on the collection, use and disclosure of Your information when You use the Service and tells You about Your privacy rights and how the law protects you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We use Your Personal data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, You agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="interpretation-and-definitions">Interpretation and Definitions&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="interpretation">Interpretation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The words of which the initial letter is capitalized have meanings defined under the following conditions. The following definitions shall have the same meaning regardless of whether they appear in singular or in plural.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trademarks</title><link>/es/trademarks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/trademarks/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="dogecoins-intellectual-property-ip">Dogecoin’s intellectual property (IP)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This intellectual property FAQ sets out a few questions that the Dogecoin Foundation is often asked
about our approach to managing IP, in accordance with our
&lt;a href="https://foundation.dogecoin.com/manifesto/">Manifesto&lt;/a> and for the benefit of the Dogecoin
community.
There are many types of IP, but for this FAQ, we are focusing on copyright and trademark as they
relate to the Dogecoin “brand”.
This FAQ does not cover issues related to the Dogecoin code, which is and will remain open-source.
For more on the Dogecoin open-source project, please see the open-source &lt;a href="https://github.com/dogecoin/dogecoin">licence
terms&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/belle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/belle/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/bluezr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/bluezr/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/cb_doge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/cb_doge/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/christinericks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/christinericks/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/dogememegirl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/dogememegirl/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/dogtorpicapollo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/dogtorpicapollo/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/ella/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/ella/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/florian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/florian/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/ishan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/ishan/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/jens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/jens/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/maniixer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/maniixer/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/michi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/michi/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/misha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/misha/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/paulo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/paulo/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/richard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/richard/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/sam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/sam/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/tiger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/tiger/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/contributors/tim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/contributors/tim/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/dogeathon-2022/main/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogeathon-2022/main/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/dogeathon-2025/main/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/dogeathon-2025/main/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/happy-birthday-kabosu-bronzethedoge/main/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/happy-birthday-kabosu-bronzethedoge/main/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/ammerwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/ammerwallet/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/arcticwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/arcticwallet/</guid><description>&lt;p>name = &amp;ldquo;Arctic Wallet&amp;rdquo;
order = “5”
active = &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo;
version = &amp;ldquo;0.9.13&amp;rdquo;
wallet_Image = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://arcticwallet.io/favicons/favicon-196x196.png%22">https://arcticwallet.io/favicons/favicon-196x196.png"&lt;/a>
website_url = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://arcticwallet.io">https://arcticwallet.io&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;
git_url = &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>download_i686_url = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://arcticwallet.io/%22">https://arcticwallet.io/"&lt;/a>
download_x86_64_url = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://arcticwallet.io/%22">https://arcticwallet.io/"&lt;/a>
download_win32_url = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://arcticwallet.io/%22">https://arcticwallet.io/"&lt;/a>
download_win64_url = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://arcticwallet.io/%22">https://arcticwallet.io/"&lt;/a>
download_MacOS_url = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://arcticwallet.io/%22">https://arcticwallet.io/"&lt;/a>
download_android_url = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.arcticmobile.app%22">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.arcticmobile.app"&lt;/a>
download_ios_url = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/arctic-wallet-mobile/id1658699963%22">https://apps.apple.com/app/arctic-wallet-mobile/id1658699963"&lt;/a>
browser_url = &amp;quot;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="wallet-classification">Wallet classification&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="wow--excelent">wow = Excelent&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="sogood--good">sogood = Good&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="suchwarning--warning">suchwarning = Warning&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>classification = &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="use-yes-or-no-to-activate-or-not-a-type">use yes or no to activate or not a type&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>type_new_user = &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo;
type_experienced_user = &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/bitpay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/bitpay/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/coinbasewallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/coinbasewallet/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/coinwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/coinwallet/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/dogechain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/dogechain/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/dogecoincore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/dogecoincore/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/dogecoinwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/dogecoinwallet/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/dogepartywallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/dogepartywallet/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/edgewallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/edgewallet/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/exodus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/exodus/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/gemwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/gemwallet/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/guarda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/guarda/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/imtoken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/imtoken/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/ledger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/ledger/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/mydoge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/mydoge/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/shapeshift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/shapeshift/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/sodogetip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/sodogetip/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/thorwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/thorwallet/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/trezor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/trezor/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/trustwallet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/trustwallet/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/es/wallets/vultisig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/es/wallets/vultisig/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>