<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dogecoin</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/</link><description>Recent content on Dogecoin</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A whale holds nearly 30% of Dogecoin supply! Is this true?</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</guid><description>The whale in question is an exchange, and so are most of the top holders in the Dogecoin network. As a matter of fact, the infamous largest whale is likely to be Robin Hood - which means it represents assets of tens of thousands of retails investors.
Use Patrick&amp;rsquo;s thread for expanding on this: https://www.reddit.com/r/dogecoin/comments/lngacy/many_fud_lets_fix_that_wow/. There is no need to specify which exchanges hold which wallets, but do explain the combination of hot/cold wallets and why exchanges use them.</description></item><item><title>Can you put a cap on Dogecoin?</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</guid><description>Dogs should wear no hats, and Doge is a dog, after all. The annual issuance is needed to pay miners and keep the network secure. Other chains, like Bitcoin, which theoretically will see their yearly issuance stop completely in 2140, will need to find a way to secure their network at that time (if it will still exist) - or they will need to change completely the design of their consensus mechanism.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin and coin burning</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-and-coin-burning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-and-coin-burning/</guid><description>Dogecoin is not a speculative asset, and it does not need coin burning mechanisms new tokens and other chains have attempted to implement to artificially inflate their prices.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin and Privacy</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-and-privacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-and-privacy/</guid><description>Are Dogecoin transactions anonymous? Are there ways shibes can protect their privacy?</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin has no developers!</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-developers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-developers/</guid><description>Oh yes it does, and it always had. Just, since Dogecoin main purpose has been to be a currency since its birth, and since it was forked from Litecoin and then reforked from Bitcoin, with changed parameters to make it more suitable as a cryptocurrency, it means it inherited already feature-complete code bases. So, for many years, instead of having new shiny features, the development team worked mostly as maintainers of what was already there.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin has no utility!</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</guid><description>Oh yes it does, and it always had. In fact, one could say it is one of the few cryptocurrencies that has been used for its main purpose from day one. Dogecoin was first meant to be a joke - and it served and will serve this purpose very well - but it almost immediately became a means to tip and encourage others to go and achieve something - the Dogecoin car, the Jamaican bobsled team, the water wells in Kenya, and many more crazy initiatives the community supported over the years.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin Inflation</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-inflation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-inflation/</guid><description>Dogecoin has a fixed yearly issuance of 5.5 billion coins. This means that each year, the rate of inflation decreases when considered against the total supply, and in a very predictable way, making Dogecoin ideal to be used as a currency. Expand on this.
https://investorplace.com/2021/02/dogecoin-has-an-inflationary-supply-trait-making-it-ideal-as-a-cryptocurrency/ https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2014/02/dogecoin-to-allow-annual-inflation-of-5-billion-coins-each-year-forever/</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin is a joke!</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-is-a-joke/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-is-a-joke/</guid><description>Dogecoin was born as a joke - and this side of it, its sense of fun, should never go away. This post should get inspiration mostly from Sporklin&amp;rsquo;s and Billy&amp;rsquo;s statements on the topic, I believe. Sporklin, a staunch defender of Dogecoin, dedicated several posts to answer this statement, at the same time contextualizing and using it as a point of strength.
https://old.reddit.com/r/dogecoin/comments/kfizst/dogepound/gg9kxe9/ https://www.reddit.com/r/dogecoindev/comments/lhtqt1/comment/gn3wz8g/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3</description></item><item><title>How can I become a Dogecoin developer?</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</guid><description>How can shibes get involved with Dogecoin development?</description></item><item><title>How can I get Dogecoin?</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/articles/get-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/pt/dogepedia/articles/get-dogecoin/</guid><description>There are many ways to get your hands on Dogecoin: from exchanges, receiving tips, accepting Dogecoin for goods and services, and even from projects like Dogecoin Folding @ Home!
Exchanges A popular way people get their hands on Dogecoin is via an exchange. There are many exchanges on the market, and they are most commonly used to exchange fiat money for cryptocurrency, or to exchange cryptocurrency for fiat money.
You can purchase Dogecoin on an exchange at the current market price (this is called a market taker transaction), or by making an offer to purchase cryptocurrency once it reaches a specified price (a market maker transaction).</description></item></channel></rss>