<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dogecoin</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/</link><description>Recent content on Dogecoin</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Operate a Dogecoin Node</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/</guid><description>The Dogecoin network is a peer-to-peer payment network consisting of thousands of computers called nodes. Each of these nodes is running specialized software, called Dogecoin Core, which can be downloaded from the official Dogecoin.com website and directly from the Github repository.
Running a full node is a service that volunteers in the network, called node operators, provide to the Dogecoin community. Unlike what happens when mining, operating a node does not lead to direct incentives or rewards, but it makes the Dogecoin network more resilient, thus contributing to utility and adoption.</description></item><item><title>A whale holds nearly 30% of Dogecoin supply! Is this true?</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</guid><description>The whale in question is an exchange, and so are most of the top holders in the Dogecoin network. As a matter of fact, the infamous largest whale is likely to be Robin Hood - which means it represents assets of tens of thousands of retails investors.
Use Patrick&amp;rsquo;s thread for expanding on this: https://www.reddit.com/r/dogecoin/comments/lngacy/many_fud_lets_fix_that_wow/. There is no need to specify which exchanges hold which wallets, but do explain the combination of hot/cold wallets and why exchanges use them.</description></item><item><title>Can you put a cap on Dogecoin?</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</guid><description>Right now, and for the next hundred years or so, Dogecoin operates like, and will continue to operate like, most other crypto assets. “Capped” assets are nowhere near mined out – and will continue adding to their supply, just like Dogecoin, for the foreseeable future.
Dogecoin’s supply is not unlimited, because it has an absolute limit of issuance per block, per day, per year – just like other coins do. The only difference is that Dogecoin’s issuance does not have an end date.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin and coin burning</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-and-coin-burning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-and-coin-burning/</guid><description>Dogecoin does not need coin burning marketing mechanisms that new tokens and other chains have attempted to implement to artificially inflate their prices.
Simplez.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin and Privacy</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-and-privacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-and-privacy/</guid><description>Privacy is an interesting topic, and one in which Dogecoin community members are actively involved. For starters, it’s worthwhile acknowledging that every transaction on the blockchain is public. That is, it’s possible for anyone to see any Dogecoin transaction that has ever been made if you have the public wallet address! This is why, if you wish to remain anonymous, it’s important not to claim any public address as yours.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin has no developers!</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-developers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-developers/</guid><description>Oh, yes it does - and it always has!
Dogecoin’s primary purpose has always been to be used as a currency. Dogecoin was originally a fork of a cryptocurrency called Luckycoin - itself a fork of Litecoin. Billy Markus, co-creator of Dogecoin with Jackson Palmer, acted as a solo developer for the first Dogecoin Core releases. In 2014, Billy and Jackson left Dogecoin development, and a new development team was formed.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin has no utility!</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</guid><description>Oh yes it does, and it always has! The simple fact is that money has utility - and Dogecoin is money! Indeed, Dogecoin is one of the few cryptocurrencies that has been used for this main purpose from day one.
Dogecoin was first meant to be a joke - and it served, and will serve, this purpose very well. It almost immediately became a means to tip and encourage others to go and achieve something: the Jamaican bobsled team, the water wells in Kenya, the Dogecoin car, and many more crazy initiatives the community supported over the years.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin Inflation</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-inflation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-inflation/</guid><description>Dogecoin has a diminished inflation rate because it has a fixed yearly issuance of 5 billion coins. This means that each year, the rate of inflation decreases comparative to the total supply, and in a very predictable way, making Dogecoin the perfect candidate to be used as a currency.
Since Dogecoin is not meant to be hoarded — and hoarding is a major barrier to a cryptocurrency being used as, well, an actual currency — Dogecoin will have a much more utilitarian and practical place in the economy than other cryptocurrencies, which often remain unspent.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin is a joke!</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-is-a-joke/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-is-a-joke/</guid><description>It is true that Dogecoin was born as a joke - and this sense of fun should forever remain and never go away! Despite Dogecoin’s genesis as a joke, though, more and more people are beginning to realise Dogecoin’s utilitarian value as a legitimate, efficient, and functional currency.
Because of this, Dogecoin has now evolved into much more than ‘just a joke’, whilst still maintaining its LOL attitude. Indeed, as the late and great Sporklin once commented: “Dogecoin can be a joke and still be functional … While the branding is frontal jokes and memes, everything under that has been solid from the start”.</description></item><item><title>How can I become a Dogecoin developer?</title><link>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://preview.dogecoin.com/fr/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</guid><description>Dogecoin is an open-source project, meaning that anyone with some technical know-how can contribute to Dogecoin’s technical development. Even if you’re new to the space, it’s never too late to learn new tricks!
Dogecoin has an amazing team of developers and volunteers who are committed to welcoming new people into the space and helping them to learn and develop their skills. For example, core developer Ross Nicoll frequently runs streams via Twitch in which newcomers and old-timers alike can participate in programming tutorials and demonstrations.</description></item></channel></rss>