<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dogecoin</title><link>/fr/</link><description>Recent content on Dogecoin</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><atom:link href="/fr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dogepedia</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/</guid><description>Dogepedia is the resource containing Documentation, Guides, FAQs and Resources related to Dogecoin. The place to be for all shibes trying to learn about Dogecoin and crypto. Such knowledge! Much wow!
Documentation Dogecoin The basics. Learn what Dogecoin is, and how it works.
What is Dogecoin? What is the history of Dogecoin? How does Dogecoin work? Who owns and controls the Dogecoin network? I want some Dogecoin! How can I get it?</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>/fr/resources/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/resources/</guid><description>A list of resources created by shibes that can be useful to work with Dogecoin and to research it.
Tools to Monitor and Study Dogecoin and its Network SoChain - Dogecoin chain explorer. Dogechain - Dogecoin chain explorer. Blockcypher - Dogecoin chain explorer. Blockshibe - monitor the work of miners and mining pools. Developed by Patrick Lodder, Dogecoin Core developer. Blockchair - monitor the number and versions of Dogecoin nodes in the network.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>/fr/legal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/legal/</guid><description>This Privacy Policy describes our policies and procedures on the collection, use and disclosure of Your information when You use the Service and tells You about Your privacy rights and how the law protects you.
We use Your Personal data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, You agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
Interpretation and Definitions Interpretation The words of which the initial letter is capitalized have meanings defined under the following conditions.</description></item></channel></rss>