<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dogecoin</title><link>/fr/</link><description>Recent content on Dogecoin</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/fr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do I backup a Dogecoin wallet?</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/articles/how-to-backup-a-wallet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/articles/how-to-backup-a-wallet/</guid><description>A wallet is just a collection of private keys and public keys.
Each one of the wallet’s private keys is a randomised 256-bit number unique to your wallet, and it is what you need to be able to access and spend your coins. Your public address - the address which other Dogecoin wallets can use to send Dogecoin to your wallet - is a hashed version of the public key associated with the private key.</description></item><item><title>A whale holds nearly 30% of Dogecoin supply! Is this true?</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</guid><description>A common source of FUD surrounding Dogecoin is the claim that certain wallets holding a large percentage of the supply are owned by private investors or so-called &amp;ldquo;whales&amp;rdquo;. In reality, many of the top Dogecoin wallets are cold wallets or hot wallets controlled by exchanges and brokers, and they thus represent Dogecoin held in custody for thousands - or hundreds of thousands, even - of people.
To those accustomed to blockchain analysis, many of those wallets appear as wallets managed by trading platforms, as they exhibit patterns of activity and volume that were typical of crypto exchanges or brokerage services holding large amounts of collateral.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin has no utility!</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</guid><description>Oh yes it does, and it always has! The simple fact is that money has utility - and Dogecoin is money! Indeed, Dogecoin is one of the few cryptocurrencies that has been used for this main purpose from day one.
Dogecoin was first meant to be a joke - and it served, and will serve, this purpose very well. It almost immediately became a means to tip and encourage others to go and achieve something: the Jamaican bobsled team, the water wells in Kenya, the Dogecoin car, and many more crazy initiatives the community supported over the years.</description></item><item><title>How can I become a Dogecoin developer?</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</guid><description>Dogecoin is an open-source project, meaning that anyone with some technical know-how can contribute to Dogecoin’s technical development. Even if you’re new to the space, it’s never too late to learn new tricks!
Dogecoin has an amazing team of developers and volunteers who are committed to welcoming new people into the space and helping them to learn and develop their skills. The community is extremely encouraging, too, and it’s very common to see old Shibes helping new Shibes as they enter the space.</description></item><item><title>How Does Dogecoin Work?</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/articles/how-does-dogecoin-work/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/articles/how-does-dogecoin-work/</guid><description>Magic and memes! (Just kidding. Kind of.)
First things first: Dogecoin is money.
Like other popular cryptocurrencies, Dogecoin works by utilising blockchain technology. Unlike a lot of other popular cryptocurrencies, though, the fees to send Dogecoin are extremely small, and the speed by which Dogecoin transactions are confirmed is relatively fast.
Simply put, if you would like to send money to someone who is located anywhere in the world — or receive money from someone who is located anywhere in the world — without using a centralised bank and paying foreign currency exchange and transfer fees, then Dogecoin can work for you!</description></item><item><title>What is a mining pool?</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/</guid><description>Mining pools are services, operated by third parties not affiliated with Dogecoin, which allow a group of miners to combine their hashing power when attempting to solve the &amp;ldquo;puzzles&amp;rdquo; involved in mining Dogecoin.
Mining rewards - consisting of 10,000 Dogecoin per block plus transaction fees associated to the transactions included in the block - are awarded to the miner who discovers a valid Proof of Work for a new block before any other miner in the network.</description></item><item><title>Operate a Dogecoin Node</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/</guid><description>The Dogecoin network is a peer-to-peer payment network consisting of thousands of computers called nodes. Each of these nodes is running specialized software. Dogecoin Core, Dogecoin&amp;rsquo;s reference implementation, is the software more commonly used to run a Dogecoin node. It can be downloaded from the official Dogecoin.com website and directly from the Github repository.
Running a full node is a service that volunteers in the network, called node operators, provide to the Dogecoin community.</description></item><item><title>Can you put a cap on Dogecoin?</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</guid><description>Right now, and for the next hundred years or so, Dogecoin operates like, and will continue to operate like, most other crypto assets. “Capped” assets are nowhere near mined out – and will continue adding to their supply, just like Dogecoin, for the foreseeable future.
Dogecoin’s supply is not unlimited, because it has an absolute limit of issuance per block, per day, per year – just like other coins do. The only difference is that Dogecoin’s issuance does not have an end date.</description></item><item><title>Charities Accepting Doge</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/articles/charities-accepting-doge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/articles/charities-accepting-doge/</guid><description>Dogecoin’s history includes many charitable endeavours: from funding clean water wells in 2014 for Kenya, to the #TeamSeas initiative in 2021 – and many worthwhile causes in-between. The past year, though, has seen a dramatic increase in charities directly accepting Dogecoin donations – which is very much wow!
Organisations like The Giving Block make it super easy for charities to accept Dogecoin and other cryptocurrency donations. Initiatives like The Water Project — which has been accepting Dogecoin for over 6-years — now use The Giving Block to accept Dogecoin donations to fund fully monitored water projects in Africa.</description></item><item><title>Dogecoin and coin burning</title><link>/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-and-coin-burning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fr/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-and-coin-burning/</guid><description>Dogecoin does not need coin burning marketing mechanisms that new tokens and other chains have attempted to implement to artificially inflate their prices.
Simplez.</description></item></channel></rss>