<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dogepedia on Dogecoin</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/</link><description>Recent content in Dogepedia on Dogecoin</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>ja</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/ja/dogepedia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do I backup a Dogecoin wallet?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-to-backup-a-wallet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-to-backup-a-wallet/</guid><description>&lt;p>A wallet is just a collection of &lt;em>private keys&lt;/em> and &lt;em>public keys&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each one of the wallet’s private keys is a randomised 256-bit number unique to your wallet, and it is what you need to be able to access and spend your coins. Your public address - the address which other Dogecoin wallets can use to send Dogecoin to your wallet - is a hashed version of the public key associated with the private key.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>あるクジラがドージコイン供給量の約30％を保有している？これは本当ですか？</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-whale-wallets/</guid><description>&lt;p>ドージコインに関するFUD（恐怖、不確実性、疑念）の一般的な原因の1つは、大量の供給量を保有する特定のウォレットが個人投資家やいわゆる「クジラ」によって所有されているという主張です。実際には、ドージコインの主要なウォレットの多くは、取引所やブローカーが管理するコールドウォレットやホットウォレットであり、それらは数千人、あるいは数十万人もの人々のために預けられているドージコインを表しています。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ブロックチェーン分析に慣れている人にとって、これらの多くのウォレットは取引プラットフォームによって管理されているウォレットのように見えます。それは、取引所や仲介サービスが大規模な担保を保持していることを示すような、典型的な取引パターンや取引量を示しているためです。特に、ドージコインコミュニティは、一部の最大規模のウォレット、そして供給量の30％を保有するとされる悪名高い「クジラ」の背後にある取引所や仲介プラットフォームを特定しました。これは、コミュニティによる状況証拠の収集や、取引所からプライベートウォレットへの入金と出金の追跡といったスルース（探偵活動）によって可能となりました。結局のところ、その悪名高いクジラウォレットは、2021年10月/11月に&lt;a href="https://bitinfocharts.com/dogecoin/wallet/3334959">複数のアドレス&lt;/a>に分割され、小売投資家数十万人の保有を含んでいることが判明しました。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>これらの取引所や仲介サービスの顧客は、これらのプラットフォームが提供するカストディアルソリューションでドージコインを保有することを自発的に選択する場合もあれば、プラットフォームがプライベートな&lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/">コールドウォレット&lt;/a>への出金を許可していないため、やむを得ずそうする場合もあります。このような状況があるたびに、ドージコインコミュニティは、これらのプラットフォームに対して出金を可能にするよう継続的かつ粘り強く要求してきました。ここ数カ月の間に、これらのサービスのいくつかがプライベートウォレットへの出金を可能にしました。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>また、コミュニティに対して分散化と非カストディアルウォレットの利点を理解することの重要性を教育することも重要です。これらは、許可不要で分散化された暗号通貨の核心をなすものです。同様に、これはドージコインエコシステムの成熟度の問題でもあることを理解することが重要です。ドージコイン向けのより多く、より優れた非カストディアルソリューションが構築されるにつれて、保有者は自己管理の利点と重要性に気付くでしょう。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>結局のところ、自分の鍵を持たないなら、自分のドージコインではありません。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can I become a Dogecoin developer?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/becoming-a-dogecoin-developer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin is an open-source project, meaning that anyone with some technical know-how can contribute to Dogecoin’s technical development. Even if you’re new to the space, it’s never too late to learn new tricks!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogecoin has an amazing team of developers and volunteers who are committed to welcoming new people into the space and helping them to learn and develop their skills. The community is extremely encouraging, too, and it’s very common to see old Shibes helping new Shibes as they enter the space.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ドージコインには実用性がない！</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/</guid><description>&lt;p>いいえ、そんなことはありません！ そして、常に実用性がありました！ シンプルな事実として、&lt;em>お金には実用性があります&lt;/em> - そしてドージコインは&lt;em>お金&lt;/em>なのです！ 実際、ドージコインは最初からこの主目的のために使用されてきた数少ない暗号&lt;strong>通貨&lt;/strong>の1つです。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ドージコインはもともと冗談として作られました - そしてその目的を非常によく果たしてきましたし、これからも果たしていくでしょう。ドージコインはほぼすぐに、人々を支援し、何かを達成するよう促すための手段となりました。ジャマイカのボブスレーチーム、ケニアの井戸、ドージコインカー、そして他にも数多くのクレイジーなイニシアチブをコミュニティが長年にわたりサポートしてきました。チップ通貨として、競合チェーンと比較して低い手数料と高速な取引のおかげで、ドージコインはその意図した使用目的を果たし続けています。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>年月を経て、オンラインストアでドージコインを使用し、支払いに利用することが可能になりました。ここ2年間で採用が急増し、BitPayやCoinbaseなどのサードパーティが提供するドージコイン支払い統合や、ドージコインを資金源としてサポートするプリペイドカードを提供する複数のプロバイダーが登場しました。ショップは、特にJSON-RPCインターフェースを通じて、ドージコインブロックチェーンと直接統合することもできます。ドージコイン財団は、開発者エコシステムと協力して、実装を簡略化および標準化するライブラリを作成することで、この統合をさらに促進する計画を立てています。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>現在もドージコインの開発が進行中で、ドージコインの元々の約束を実現し、他の暗号通貨と競争力を持たせるための改良が行われています。現在、複数の開発者グループがドージコインおよびそのエコシステムのために開発を進めており、ドージコインは新たな目的や用途を見つけていくでしょう。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://foundation.dogecoin.com/manifesto/">ドージコインマニフェスト&lt;/a>にもあるように、ドージコインはユニークな楽しさの感覚を維持しながら、実用性、親しみやすさ、おもてなしの心、信頼性に焦点を当てることを目指しています。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Does Dogecoin Work?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-does-dogecoin-work/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-does-dogecoin-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>Magic and memes! (Just kidding. Kind of.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First things first: Dogecoin &lt;em>is&lt;/em> money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like other popular cryptocurrencies, Dogecoin works by utilising &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-blockchain/">blockchain technology&lt;/a>. Unlike a lot of other popular cryptocurrencies, though, the fees to send Dogecoin are extremely small, and the speed by which Dogecoin transactions are confirmed is relatively fast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/11.png" alt="image info">
Simply put, if you would like to send money to someone who is located anywhere in the world — or receive money from someone who is located anywhere in the world — &lt;em>without&lt;/em> using a centralised bank and paying foreign currency exchange and transfer fees, then Dogecoin can work for you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a mining pool?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mining pools are services, operated by third parties not affiliated with Dogecoin, which allow a group of &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/">&lt;strong>miners&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> to combine their &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/#hashing-power">&lt;strong>hashing power&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> when attempting to solve the &amp;ldquo;puzzles&amp;rdquo; involved in mining Dogecoin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mining rewards&lt;/strong> - consisting of 10,000 Dogecoin per block plus transaction fees associated to the transactions included in the block - are awarded to the miner who discovers a valid Proof of Work for a new block before any other miner in the network. Anyhow, alone, a miner has a very limited hashing power in relation to the overall &lt;strong>Mining Hashrate&lt;/strong> of the network. This means a miner, even when using a powerful &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/how-tos/mining-dogecoin/#ASICs">&lt;strong>ASIC miner&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, has a small chance at being awarded the next block. In practice, it could take a long time before a solo miner finds a block and is awarded the rewards associated with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Operate a Dogecoin Node</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Dogecoin network is a peer-to-peer payment network consisting of thousands of computers called &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/">&lt;strong>nodes&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>. Each of these nodes is running specialized software. &lt;strong>Dogecoin Core&lt;/strong>, Dogecoin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>reference implementation&lt;/em>, is the software more commonly used to run a Dogecoin node. It can be downloaded from the official &lt;a href="https://dogecoin.com/">&lt;strong>Dogecoin.com&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> website and directly from the &lt;a href="https://github.com/dogecoin/dogecoin/releases">&lt;strong>Github repository&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Running a &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/#full-nodes">&lt;strong>full node&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> is a service that volunteers in the network, called &lt;em>node operators&lt;/em>, provide to the Dogecoin community. Unlike what happens when mining, operating a node does not lead to direct incentives or rewards, but it makes the Dogecoin network more resilient, thus contributing to utility and adoption.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Charities Accepting Doge</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/charities-accepting-doge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/charities-accepting-doge/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin’s history includes many charitable endeavours: from funding clean water wells in 2014 for Kenya, to the #TeamSeas initiative in 2021 – and many worthwhile causes in-between. The past year, though, has seen a dramatic increase in charities directly accepting Dogecoin donations – which is very much wow!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Organisations like &lt;em>The Giving Block&lt;/em> make it super easy for charities to accept Dogecoin and other cryptocurrency donations. Initiatives like &lt;em>The Water Project&lt;/em> — which has been accepting Dogecoin for over 6-years — now use &lt;em>The Giving Block&lt;/em> to accept Dogecoin donations to fund fully monitored water projects in Africa. The &lt;em>American Cancer Society&lt;/em> is also another charity that utilises this service, and uses Dogecoin donations to help patients access lifesaving care and resources, as they work toward the goal of ridding the world from cancer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dogecoin and Privacy</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-and-privacy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-and-privacy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Privacy is an interesting topic, and one in which Dogecoin community members are actively involved. For starters, it’s worthwhile acknowledging that every transaction on the blockchain is public. That is, it’s possible for anyone to see any Dogecoin transaction that has ever been made if you have the public wallet address! This is why, if you wish to remain anonymous, it’s important not to claim any public address as yours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can I get Dogecoin?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/get-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/get-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many ways to get your hands on Dogecoin: from exchanges, receiving tips, accepting Dogecoin for goods and services, and even from projects like Dogecoin Folding @ Home!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="exchanges">Exchanges&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A popular way people get their hands on Dogecoin is via an exchange. There are many exchanges on the market, and they are most commonly used to exchange fiat money for cryptocurrency, or to exchange cryptocurrency for fiat money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can purchase Dogecoin on an exchange at the current market price (this is called a market &lt;em>taker&lt;/em> transaction), or by making an offer to purchase cryptocurrency once it reaches a specified price (a market &lt;em>maker&lt;/em> transaction). Some exchanges only allow its users to purchase cryptocurrencies via market taker transactions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can I help?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-can-i-help-doge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-can-i-help-doge/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are &lt;em>so&lt;/em> many ways to get involved and support Dogecoin. From making memes and artworks – to educating people who are new to crypto: there are endless possibilities for you to get involved and to help the Dogecoin movement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good place to start is by joining one or more of the highly active communities on platforms such as &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dogecoin/">Reddit&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dogecoin">Twitter&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/X3fHfpvpCM">Discord&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a technical background and would like to contribute to Dogecoin technical development, you can get involved via &lt;a href="https://github.com/dogecoin/dogecoin">Dogecoin Core&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/dogecoinfoundation">The Dogecoin Foundation&lt;/a> GitHub repositories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can I join the Dogecoin community?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/join-the-dogecoin-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/join-the-dogecoin-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are many ways you can get involved in the Dogecoin community! Most popular social-media platforms have a thriving and welcoming Dogecoin community through which newcomers and old-timers alike can connect, discuss, and share their thoughts, memes, ideas, and spread the joy of all things Doge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Reddit&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Twitter&lt;/strong> are the most popular platforms for the Dogecoin community, with millions of active Shibes on either platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Reddit, &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/dogecoin/">r/dogecoin&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> is so popular that in 2021 it was ranked as Reddit’s Top community for cryptocurrency and finance, and posts in the Dogecoin subreddit are frequently the most upvoted posts for the entire Reddit platform! If you are more technically inclined and want to stay updated about Dogecoin development, you can also check out the technical development subreddit at &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/dogecoindev/">r/dogecoindev&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>. &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/dogeducation/">r/dogeducation&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> is another subreddit where new Dogecoin users can find How-Tos and help.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can I use Dogecoin to buy stuff from my favorite stores?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/using-dogecoin-in-a-store/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/using-dogecoin-in-a-store/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin is becoming increasingly popular as a payment option by merchants worldwide. Moreover, the implementation of third-party cryptocurrency payment solutions such as Coinbase Commerce and BitPay has resulted in more-and-more businesses accepting Dogecoin. It is also possible for you to indirectly use Dogecoin at merchants who don’t accept Dogecoin. For example, some companies have established relationships with credit card companies in which you can &amp;rsquo;top up&amp;rsquo; a credit card from your Dogecoin crypto wallet. Other companies even facilitate the payments of utilities and bills with Dogecoin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can my business accept Dogecoin?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-can-my-business-accept-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-can-my-business-accept-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>The past year has seen a wave of businesses starting to accept Dogecoin for goods and services. Thanks to a multitude of crypto payment solutions, now it’s as easy as ever for your business to accept Dogecoin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the most foundational level, for your business to accept Dogecoin in exchange for goods and services you will require a &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/">wallet&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a bricks-and-mortar business where payments are made in person, it’s common for merchants to print a QR code that is scanned by customers’ smartphones to streamline the transaction process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How do I get a Dogecoin wallet?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/</guid><description>&lt;p>A wallet is necessary for people wanting to trade, use, or ‘hodl’ Dogecoin. There are many ways you can get a wallet, and the best choice of wallet for you is dependent upon the purpose for which you intend to use your Dogecoin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Generally speaking, there are two overarching categories of wallets: &amp;lsquo;custodial&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;non-custodial&amp;rsquo;, depending on whether you are the sole holder of your wallet&amp;rsquo;s private key. Additionally, wallets can be &amp;lsquo;hot&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;cold&amp;rsquo;, depending on whether they are connected to the internet or not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How do I send and receive Dogecoin?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/send-and-receive-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/send-and-receive-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sending and receiving Dogecoin is very easy to do. Whether you intend to send or receive Dogecoin, in both cases you will need a &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/">wallet&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When sending Dogecoin from your wallet you will need to input a destination wallet address. This is a unique alphanumeric identifier that looks a bit like gibberish! Rest assured, though, a wallet address is certainly &lt;em>not&lt;/em> gibberish – but specifies a unique destination on the Dogecoin blockchain to which Dogecoin can be sent and stored.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is there a roadmap?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-roadmap/</guid><description>&lt;p>While a &amp;lsquo;roadmap&amp;rsquo; is a term that&amp;rsquo;s commonly used when new cryptocurrencies are released,
it also conveys a rigid way forward, led by a single ‘company’ or ‘lead developer’.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogecoin is a community-driven, consensus based open-source project and its direction is
formed by the many individual and organisational contributors to the various projects of
the Dogecoin blockchain &amp;amp; ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The direction of Dogecoin is paved by the &lt;a href="/dogepedia/projects/">many projects&lt;/a> that the
community feels best shape its direction. This is very intentional: it is important
that Dogecoin remains a decentralised project with shepherds rather than rulers, whose projects
and contributions stand or fall on their merits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is xxx project affiliated with The Dogecoin Foundation?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/is-this-project-affiliated-with-dogecoin-foundation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/is-this-project-affiliated-with-dogecoin-foundation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Making Memes</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/how-tos/making-memes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/how-tos/making-memes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Memes are awesome, and they’re easy to make! There’s lots of meme maker websites, and even meme applications that you can install on your smartphone to makes memes on the run. You may even go one step further and create Dogecoin-themed meme templates which have a possibility of being seen by millions of others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What makes a great meme? Well, it needs to be funny and convey meaning in a concise and relatable form. Moreover, capturing the sentiment of a community – or peoples’ innermost thoughts and feelings that are not shared publicly – can form a great basis from which to create highly engaging and novel memes. The power of memes also comes from their accessibility and ability to be viewed by millions in a relatively short of amount of time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mining Dogecoin</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/how-tos/mining-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/how-tos/mining-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Miners and mining are at the center of Dogecoin&amp;rsquo;s Proof of Work consensus mechanism. Check these Dogepedia articles to understand what miners do, how they interact with nodes, and why mining pools come into play when it comes to mining:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/">&lt;strong>What is a miner?&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/">&lt;strong>What is a mining pool?&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/">&lt;strong>What is a node?&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="mining-dogecoin">Mining Dogecoin&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Mining Dogecoin used to be much simpler in the early days. A miner only needed a computer with enough disk space and a gaming GPU - and this was enough to mine Dogecoin. Soon enough, the total &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/#hashing-power">&lt;strong>mining hashrate of the network&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> had grown so much that the likelihood of a miner finding a block while mining solo had been reduced drastically.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The History of Dogecoin</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/history-of-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/history-of-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin was originally created as a joke in late 2013 by Billy Markus and Jackson Palmer. Both Billy and Jackson thought that cryptocurrency was being taken far too seriously and wasn’t much fun. Jackson created the Dogecoin.com website and would have been, for a while, the public face of Dogecoin, while Billy worked as a solo developer on the first 4 releases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/12.png" alt="image info">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On December 6th, 2013, Dogecoin was launched taking influence from the famous Doge meme: an image of a very adorable Shiba Inu dog with multi-coloured comic sans text that appears as the dog’s “thought bubbles”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What are the benefits of a hardware wallet, and how to use it with Doge?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>&lt;p>A hardware wallet is a device designed to store a user&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>private keys&lt;/em> securely, without ever exposing them to other external devices or the internet. For this reason, most hardware wallets are &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/how-do-i-get-a-wallet/">cold wallets&lt;/a> and are amongst the most secure methods for storing and using Dogecoin and other cryptos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually, hardware wallets can be connected to a PC or another device via a USB or Bluetooth connection. Through this connection, they can be used to sign a transaction occurring in a wallet application running on the external device (such as your PC). The transaction is signed inside the hardware wallet, and, unless the hardware wallet has been previously compromised, the private keys are never exposed to the outside world throughout this process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a blockchain?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-blockchain/</guid><description>&lt;p>A blockchain is a digital distributed ledger that is used as a system for validating and recording transaction information. This digital ledger of transactions is duplicated and distributed throughout an entire network of computers connected to the blockchain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Dogecoin blockchain consists of thousands of computers – called &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/">&lt;strong>nodes&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> – meaning that transaction information is not stored in one centralised place. Instead, Dogecoin blockchain information is stored across thousands of nodes. This is why cryptocurrencies like Dogecoin are often referred to as being &lt;em>decentralised&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a miner?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-miner/</guid><description>&lt;p>A &lt;strong>Miner&lt;/strong> is a specialized &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/">node&lt;/a> in the Dogecoin network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After regular &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/#full-nodes">nodes&lt;/a> in the network, by referencing the blockchain, have verified that a Dogecoin transaction is valid, the transaction is shown in a &amp;ldquo;pending&amp;rdquo; state. It stays in this state until a &lt;strong>miner&lt;/strong> or a collective of miners known as a &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-mining-pool/">&lt;strong>mining pool&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> picks up the transaction.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="miners-eli5">Miners: ELI5&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Miners are nodes using special hardware (normally Scrypt ASIC miners) which allows them to solve cryptographic puzzles, in a process referred to as &amp;ldquo;mining&amp;rdquo;. A miner receives new transactions from the other nodes in the network, combines them in a &lt;strong>block&lt;/strong> following predetermined and inviolable rules enforced by the network, and then attempts to solve a puzzle that will generate a special number, called a hash, that is derived by combining the content of the block and a number called &lt;strong>nonce&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>number used once&lt;/em>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a node and why is it important? Do I need to run one?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Dogecoin network is a peer-to-peer payment network consisting of thousands of computers called nodes. Each of these nodes is running specialized software, called Dogecoin Core. Transaction information is recorded into a database, split into blocks chained to each other, and distributed and replicated across the nodes of the network: this database is known as the &lt;em>Dogecoin blockchain&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In practice, this results in transaction information being shared across the entire network and, subsequently, not needing to be stored in one centralized place. This is why cryptocurrencies like Dogecoin are often referred to as being &lt;em>decentralized&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a wallet, really?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-wallet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-wallet/</guid><description>&lt;p>A wallet is a set of private keys that gives you access to the control of certain coins on the blockchain ledger. When you spend a coin, control of that coin is transferred from being controlled by your keys to being controlled by someone else&amp;rsquo;s keys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A &lt;em>wallet app&lt;/em> (often referred to simply as a &amp;ldquo;wallet&amp;rdquo;) is an application which manages these keys, reports these amounts, and facilitates the transfer of amounts of coins between addresses. Some wallet apps store your keys locally; others store the keys on a remote server (which is less safe). Just remember: &lt;em>whoever has the keys controls the coins&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is Dogecoin Folding @ Home?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-folding-at-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-folding-at-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dogecoin Folding at Home is a charitable community-based distributed-computing project that utilises participants’ idle computer power to help scientists who are studying COVID-19, Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s, Huntington&amp;rsquo;s, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s, cancers and other diseases as they work towards finding cures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It uses a very simple GUI interface, and runs in the background using idle computer time via GPUs, CPUs, and ARM processors. Your computer will receive “work units”, and then sends the completed work units back to the FAH servers. These are then compiled with other work units into an overall statistical simulation pertaining to one or more diseases and their potential therapies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is Dogecoin?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/3.png" alt="image info">
Dogecoin is many things to many different people. At its heart, Dogecoin is the accidental crypto &lt;strong>movement&lt;/strong> that makes people smile!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is also an open-source peer-to-peer cryptocurrency that utilises &lt;a href="https://www.dogecoin.com/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-blockchain">blockchain technology&lt;/a>, a highly secure decentralised system of storing information as a public ledger that is maintained by a network of computers called &lt;a href="https://www.dogecoin.com/dogepedia/articles/what-is-a-node">nodes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More than this, though, is the ethos of Dogecoin, summarised in the &lt;a href="https://foundation.dogecoin.com/manifesto/">Dogecoin Manifesto&lt;/a>, and its amazing, vibrant community made up of friendly folks just like you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is the Dogecoin Foundation?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-the-dogecoin-foundation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/what-is-the-dogecoin-foundation/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Dogecoin Foundation is a not-for-profit organisation tasked with providing (i) support for Dogecoin through development and advocacy, (ii) Dogecoin trademark defence to prevent abuse and fraud, and (iii) a roadmap and governance for the future of Dogecoin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Foundation was initially established by members of the Dogecoin team in 2014 to provide governance and support for the Dogecoin project. In 2021 the Foundation was re-invigorated by members of the core development team — along with fresh faces and new seasoned advisors — ready to grow Dogecoin for the decade ahead!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What merchants currently accept Dogecoin?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/merchants-accepting-doge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/merchants-accepting-doge/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the time of writing, there is a rapidly expanding list of merchants who accept Dogecoin as a form of payment. Because of this, finding — and maintaining — an up-to-date directory of businesses that #AcceptDoge is no small feat!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to the overwhelming support from the Dogecoin community in encouraging — and then promoting — businesses that accept Dogecoin, we anticipate that the list of businesses that accept Dogecoin is only going to grow much larger and cover a variety of industries and sectors in the years to come. This is certainly the aim: the Dogecoin community is committed to seeing Dogecoin used as a viable alternative to traditional centralised fiat money.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who are the current Dogecoin developers?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-developers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/dogecoin-developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>The development of Dogecoin is open, permissionless, and participatory. Over the years, a varied group of developers has contributed to the development of Dogecoin Core, Dogecoin&amp;rsquo;s reference implementation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dogecoin was created by Billy Markus and Jackson Palmer in 2013. Billy worked on Dogecoin Core as its main developer for its first releases. Dogecoin Core started as a fork of Lucky Coin and Litecoin, themselves forks of Bitcoin Core. Dogecoin Core thus derived most of its codebase from the work Bitcoin developers had done on the Bitcoin repository.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who owns and controls the Dogecoin Network?</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/articles/who-owns-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/articles/who-owns-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the wonderful things about Dogecoin is that no-one, or no corporate entity, “owns” the Dogecoin blockchain: it is entirely open-source, permissionless, decentralised, and peer-to-peer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Dogecoin network is “controlled” by the network of nodes through which it operates. Anyone can run a node, and to learn how to do so, &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/how-tos/operating-a-node/">click here&lt;/a>. Some nodes also &lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/how-tos/mining-dogecoin/">mine Dogecoin&lt;/a>, meaning they perform computational work as part of the process to both confirm all transactions up to the next block, and the next block. They are rewarded for this work with a block reward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ドージコインとコインバーン</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-and-coin-burning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-and-coin-burning/</guid><description>&lt;p>ドージコインは、新しいトークンや他のチェーンが価格を人工的に引き上げるために試みているコインバーンのようなマーケティングメカニズムを必要としません。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>簡単ですね。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/8.png" alt="画像情報">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ドージコインには開発者がいない！</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-developers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>いいえ、ちゃんといます！ そして、ずっと存在しています！&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ドージコインの主な目的は常に通貨として使用されることでした。ドージコインはもともとLuckycoinという暗号通貨（Litecoinをフォークしたもの）のフォークとして誕生しました。ドージコインの共同創設者であるビリー・マーカスとジャクソン・パーマーが、最初のDogecoin Coreリリースの単独開発者として活躍しました。2014年、ビリーとジャクソンがドージコインの開発から離れ、新しい開発チームが結成されました。これまでの年月で、ドージコイン開発チームは40人以上の貢献者の仕事を調整する小規模なメンテナンスチームで構成されてきました。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2015年、Dogecoin Core 1.10.0から、ドージコイン開発チームはドージコインをビットコインを基に再フォークし、その上にLitecoinの変更を適用する決定をしました。その結果、ドージコインはその歴史を通じてすでに完成されたコードベースを受け継ぎ、ビットコインと多くの部分で共通する特徴を持っています。一方で、ドージコインの独自性は、変更されたパラメータや最適化、そしてLitecoinやビットコインから継承されなかったコードの一部から生まれています。これらの変更は常に、ドージコインを日常で使用できる実用的な通貨にすることを目指し、利便性と使いやすさに重点を置いて行われました。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>将来的には、ドージコインを「人々の通貨」としての目的を達成するために、さらに多くの努力とリソースを投入する計画です。そのためには、パートタイムの貢献者やボランティアに加え、開発者やエンジニアを含むフルタイムのスタッフも必要になります。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ドージコイン財団の&lt;a href="https://foundation.dogecoin.com/trailmap/">旅のしおり&lt;/a>では、「人々のための通貨」という共通の目標に向かって進むエコシステムの中でさまざまなプロジェクトがリストアップされています。この旅のしおりは絶対的な指針ではなく、コミュニティからのフィードバックを受け入れる形で進む方向性を示すものです。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>実際の作業の多くはこのリポジトリ外で行われていますが、一部の開発活動はGitHubの&lt;a href="https://github.com/dogecoin/dogecoin">&lt;strong>Dogecoin Coreリポジトリ&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>で確認することができます。また、redditの&lt;a href="https://reddit.com/r/dogecoindev">&lt;strong>r/dogecoindev&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>も、ドージコインの開発について話し合ったり、開発者と交流したりするのに適したチャンネルです。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ドージコインに供給上限を設定できますか？</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/faq/putting-a-cap-on-dogecoin/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/7.png" alt="画像情報">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>現在、そして今後100年ほどの間、ドージコインは他の多くの暗号資産と同じように機能しており、これからも同様に機能し続けます。「供給上限がある」資産もまだ採掘が終わる気配はなく、今後もドージコインと同じように供給を増やし続けるでしょう。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ドージコインの供給量は&lt;strong>無制限&lt;/strong>ではありません。1ブロックごと、1日ごと、1年ごとに発行量の絶対的な制限が存在します。他のコインと同様です。ただし、唯一の違いは、ドージコインの発行に終了日が設定されていないことです。したがって、ドージコインは「無限の時間」においてのみ「無限」と言えます。有限の時間内では、その発行量は実際には有限です。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>この年間発行量は、マイナーへの報酬を提供し、ネットワークを安全に保つために必要です。例えばビットコインのような他のチェーンでは、理論的には2140年に年間発行量が完全に停止する予定ですが、その時点でネットワークを安全に保つ方法を見つける必要があります（その時点でまだ存在している場合）。そうでなければ、コンセンサスメカニズムの設計を完全に変更する必要があるでしょう。簡単に言えば、ドージコインに供給上限を設定すると、ネットワークが安全ではなくなり、攻撃に対して脆弱になってしまいます。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ドージコインのインフレ</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-inflation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-inflation/</guid><description>&lt;p>ドージコインは年間発行量が50億枚に固定されているため、インフレ率が減少しています。これは、毎年インフレ率が総供給量と比較して&lt;strong>減少&lt;/strong>し、非常に予測可能な方法で進むことを意味します。この特徴により、ドージコインは通貨として使用するのに最適な候補となっています。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ドージコインは貯め込むことを目的としていないため、（そして貯め込むことは暗号&lt;strong>通貨&lt;/strong>が実際の&lt;strong>通貨&lt;/strong>として使われる上で大きな障害となるため）、ドージコインは他の暗号通貨よりも経済においてはるかに実用的で実際的な役割を果たすことができます。多くの暗号通貨が未使用のままであることが多い中、ドージコインはより活発に利用される可能性があります。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/10.png" alt="画像情報">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ドージコインはおあそびなのか！</title><link>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-is-a-joke/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-is-a-joke/</guid><description>&lt;p>確かに、ドージコインはおあそびとして誕生しました - そして、この楽しさの感覚は永遠に残り続け、消えることはありません！ しかし、ドージコインが冗談として始まったにもかかわらず、ますます多くの人々がドージコインの実用的な価値を、正当で効率的、かつ機能的な通貨として認識し始めています。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>このため、ドージコインは「ただのおあそび」を超えた存在へと進化しましたが、その「LOL」な態度は維持しています。実際、故スパークリンがかつてこうコメントしたように：「ドージコインはおあそびでありながら機能的であることができます … ブランディングがジョークやミームで構成されている一方、その下にあるものは最初からしっかりしていました」。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>事実、他の暗号通貨とは異なり、ドージコインはその誕生時からユースケース（使用目的）を持ち、それに伴う実用性を備えていました。2013年12月のローンチから数日後、チップを簡単に送れるチッピングボットが利用可能となり、reddit上でユーザー同士が気軽にチップを送り合うことができました。取引のスピードと低手数料のおかげで、しばらくの間、ドージコインはreddit上で「チップ用暗号通貨」としての地位を築きました。同時に、コミュニティは多くの素晴らしい目的や慈善活動のためにドージコインを集め始めました。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ドージコインの歴史については&lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/articles/history-of-dogecoin/">こちら&lt;/a>、実用性については&lt;a href="/ja/dogepedia/faq/dogecoin-has-no-utility/">こちら&lt;/a>をご覧ください。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/assets/images/dogepedia/9.png" alt="画像情報">&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>